this problem deals with handling user
input
whenever we receive user input we want
to store it into a variable so that
we're able to
compare or use its value later on
in this example we want the user to
input
4 and if they don't input 4 then we want
to continue our loop of
asking them this question what does 2
plus 2 equal
so we want to just continue asking them
until they input the correct answer
the code we've been given is already set
up to prompt the user
and store their input in a variable
and we can demonstrate that by just
disregarding this loop for a moment
and will prompt the user
and then spit their input back out at
them
so let's run the program and if i input
the program spits 5 back out at me
if i input 4 it prints 4.
so you can see how we've stored the user
input here
in the local variable answer
also of note here is that user input
will always be a string
so you can see that on line 3 we've
called the 2i method on that string
in order to convert the user's input
into an integer so let's go back to our
loop structure
the problem requirements tell us to
output the string
that's correct and then break out of
this loop
if the user input is four
otherwise we want to output a string
telling them that they're wrong
and the loop will keep running
so we can use an if statement to check
the value of user input
now we only care whether it's equal to
4.
and if it is we want to tell the user
they're correct
[Music]
and break out of our loop
so let's run the code as is
[Music]
okay and you can see when we input four
we're told we're correct and our program
exited
now let's run it one more time and input
something other than
4 and you can see that the program will
just keep prompting us
because the loop is still running we
must input 4 to break out of that loop
so we're just missing one piece to our
problem here and that's
outputting a message to the user when
they don't input four
so we want to tell them they're wrong
and to try again
[Music]
and now we can see that message output
to us when we input anything that's not
four
and finally we'll input 4 and exit our
loop
[Music]
if we had not converted the user input
to an integer
using the 2i method
then this comparison on line 5 comparing
answer to the integer 4
would always evaluate to false
[Music]
as you can see if i input 4 now
i'll be told i'm wrong this comparison
will never equal true
because we are comparing the string 4
to the integer 4.
if i changed my comparison on line 4 to
compare the answer variable
to the string 4
[Music]
then those two values would be evaluated
as equal
[Music]
so it's important to always be conscious
of
what data type you're working with and
remember that
user input always comes in as a string